Guide to the Records of American Association for Ethiopian Jews (AAEJ), undated, 1960-1961, 1963, 1965-1968, 1970-1995, 2001-2002 *I-503
American Jewish Historical Society, Boston, MA and New York, NY
- Subgroup II: AAEJ Activists, undated, 1961, 1963, 1966, 1968, 1970-1993; Boxes 38-139.
  - Series A: LaDena Schnapper (AAEJ Coordinator) Files, undated, 1961, 1963, 1966, 1968, 1970-1991; Boxes 38-120.
    - Subseries 3: Schnapper's Chicago AAEJ General Files A-Z, undated, 1961, 1966, 1971, 1973, 1975, 1977-1990; Boxes 90-120.
      - Williams, Robert Lawrence, 1983-1984, 1986, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 18)
      - Winn, Michael - National Jewish Monthly article, undated, 1981 (Box 119, Folder 19)
      - Winnepeg Committee for Ethiopian Jews - Levine, Elliot, undated, 1983-1988, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 20)
      - WIZO, 1985-1986 (Box 119, Folder 21)
      - Wondemu Hagos - Ethiopian-Israel, 1988-1989 (Box 119, Folder 22)
      - Woods, Harriet, 1986 (Box 119, Folder 23)
      - Work History Forms, undated (Box 119, Folder 24)
      - World Jewish Genealogy Organization, undated (Box 119, Folder 25)
      - World Newsmap (see OS6F Folder 1), 1985 (Box 119, Folder 26)
      - World Refugee Service, 1984 (Box 119, Folder 27)
      - World Relief, undated, 1982-1985 (Box 119, Folder 28)
      - World Service Authority, undated (Box 119, Folder 29)
      - World Vision, undated, 1983-1987 (Box 120, Folder 1-2)
      - WUJS, 1983, 1985 (Box 120, Folder 3)
      - WUJS Proposal - May 1987 (Box 120, Folder 4)
      - Wunderman Foundation, 1984 (Box 120, Folder 5)
      - Xerox, 1984 (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - Yisrael, Yehiel, 1986-1987 (Box 120, Folder 7)
      - Yohannes Tiku - Ethiopian-U.S., undated, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box 120, Folder 8)
      - Yosef, Abraham (Avi), 1987 (Box 120, Folder 9)
      - Youth for Understanding, undated, 1984-1986 (Box 120, Folder 10)
      - Zarechi, Mark, 1987 (Box 120, Folder 11)
      - Zeiler, Claudia, 1986 (Box 120, Folder 12)
      - Zelazo, Ziona, 1988-1989 (Box 120, Folder 13)
      - Zeller, Jack, 1988, 1990 (Box 120, Folder 14)
      - Zemere, Dawit - Ethiopian-Israel, 1986, 1988-1989 (Box 120, Folder 15)
      - Zewditu, Motbaynor - Ethiopian-Israel, 1989-1990 (Box 120, Folder 16)
      - Zimmerman, Marvin, undated, 1982, 1984-1985 (Box 120, Folder 17)
      - Zionist Organization of America, 1983-1984 (Box 120, Folder 18)
      - Zober, Mark, undated (Box 120, Folder 19)
      - Zonis, Marvin, 1985 (Box 120, Folder 20)
      - Zucker, Rabbi Daniel, undated, 1986 (Box 120, Folder 21)
  - Series B: William Recant, undated, 1979, 1981-1993; Boxes 121-130.
    William Recant was the first executive director of the AAEJ in Washington, D.C. from 1984 to 1993. He was an experienced, effective advocate and expert in international relations.28 Recant briefed President George Bush on the condition of Ethiopian Jews in Israel and those remaining in Ethiopia and worked closely with the Special Israeli Envoy as liaison to the U.S. Government in the planning and implementation of Operation Solomon.29 Recant, on behalf of the AAEJ, helped establish the Congressional Caucus for Ethiopian Jews which served as the leading advocate for the rights of Ethiopian Jews. More than 155 members of Congress belonged to the cause.30 Recant advised State Department officials and members of Congress on Ethiopian Jewry and spoke to groups nationwide on the plight of the Ethiopian community.31 Recant advocated for continued rescue and relief of the Ethiopian Jews. Recant had previously done work to help Soviet Jews.
    The series is composed of Will Recant's general files as well as correspondence with politicians collected by Recant while serving as executive director of the AAEJ from 1984 to 1993 in the Washington, DC office.
    - Subseries 1: Recant General Files, undated, 1979, 1981-1993; Boxes 121-128.
      The subseries contains Recant's general files, arranged alphabetically by folder title. Files of significant interest to researchers in this subseries are the AAEJ board meeting minutes, correspondence with various temples and congregations, correspondence with local Jewish organizations, files on Ethiopia (famine, resettlement, Ethiopian villages, and general information), international family reunification plan files, and Surgical Aid to Children of the World (SACOW) relief trip reports.
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, October 29, 1983 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, April 8, 1984 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, October 21, 1984 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, November 3, 1985 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, September 13, 1986 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting September 13, 1986, 1984-1987 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, November 8, 1987 (Box 121, Folder 7)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, October 16, 1988 (Box 121, Folder 8)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, November 5, 1989 (Box 121, Folder 9)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, June 30, 1991 (Box 121, Folder 10)
      - AAEJ Board Meeting, 1993 (Box 121, Folder 11)
      - Annual Board Meeting Response, 1987 (Box 121, Folder 12)
      - AAEJ: National Conference 1983 (contains negatives and contact sheet), undated, 1982-1984 (Box 121, Folder 13)
      - AAEJ: National Conference Fall 1986 (contains negatives and contact sheet) (Box 121, Folder 14)
      - AAEJ Offices, undated, 1989-1992 (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - AAEJ: Programs, Operations and Organizational Opportunities: Proposal and Correspondence, undated, 1986-1988 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - AAEJ: Printouts, undated, 1986-1988 (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - AAEJ: Rabbinic Call to Conscience (contains photographs), Fall 1986 (Box 122, Folder 4)
      - AAEJ: Reunion of 400 Ethiopian Jews Rescue in Israel, 1985 (Box 122, Folder 5)
      - AAEJ: Solidarity Demonstration and Week in Israel, 1984 (Box 122, Folder 6)
      - AAEJ Speakers Bureau, undated (Box 122, Folder 7)
      - AAEJ Update, undated, 1991-1992 (Box 122, Folder 8)
      - ACIAD/ORAD, 1985-1986 (Box 122, Folder 9)
      - Adas Israel Congregation (Washington, DC), undated, 1989-1990 (Box 122, Folder 10)
      - Adas Israel - Checks for Debra's paintings, 1991 (Box 122, Folder 11)
      - Temple Adath Israel (Rabbi Jonathan Adland), 1988-1990 (Box 122, Folder 12)
      - Adath Jeshurun Congregation (Minneapolis, Minn. 55408), 1990 (Box 122, Folder 13)
      - Agudas Achim (Alexandria, VA), 1990 (Box 122, Folder 14)
      - Congregation Ahavath Achim, 1989-1990 (Box 122, Folder 15)
      - Asner, Ed (contains photograph), undated, 1986 (Box 122, Folder 16)
      - Bachrach, undated, 1988-1989 (Box 122, Folder 17)
      - Baron de Hirsch Fund, 1985-1987 (Box 122, Folder 18)
      - Becker, David, 1988-1989 (Box 122, Folder 19)
      - [Jewish Congregation of] Belair Nevey Shalom (Bowie, MD 20715) (122 Torah Ln), 1990 (Box 122, Folder 20)
      - Bengualid, Sylvia (Rabbi Marc Angel), 1988-1989 (Box 122, Folder 21)
      - Berman, Colette, 1989 (Box 122, Folder 22)
      - Congregation Beth David, 1989-1990 (Box 122, Folder 23)
      - Beth El - Bethesda, MD, 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 1)
      - Beth El - Oneonta, NY, 1990-1991 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Beth El - San Diego, CA, December 8-10, ? (Box 123, Folder 3)
      - Beth Emet - Reston, VA (Joan Reed), 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 4)
      - Beth Israel Congregation (Ann Arbor, MI, 48104), 1989 (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - Temple Beth Shalom (Toms River, NJ), 1990 (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - Beth Tikva - Rockville, MD, 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 7)
      - Beth Tikvah (Lake Worth Jewish Center, FL), 1989 (Box 123, Folder 8)
      - Beth Torah Congregation (West Hyattsville, MD 20782), 1990 (Box 123, Folder 9)
      - Block, Stacey and Jacqui Rick, 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 10)
      - Bloomington, Ind. Community, 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 11)
      - B'nai Abraham Sisterhood (Hagerstown, MD 21740), 1990 (Box 123, Folder 12)
      - Congregation B'nai David (Southfield, MI 48075), 1990 (Box 123, Folder 13)
      - B'nai Shalom of Olney, MD, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 14)
      - Boston JCRC, Owen Kuperschmid, 1983-1984, 1988-1989 (Box 123, Folder 15)
      - Congregation Brith Sholom (Bethlehem, PA 18017), 1990 (Box 123, Folder 16)
      - Brochures, Newsletters, etc., undated, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 17)
      - Bronfman, Edgar, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 123, Folder 18)
      - Brownstein, Steve (contains photographs), undated, 1987-1989 (Box 123, Folder 19)
      - Camp Kutz, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 20)
      - Camp Programs, undated, 1984, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 21)
      - Capital District Community (Riemer, Dorit Stark), 1988 (Box 123, Folder 22)
      - Central Conference of American Rabbis, 1991 (Box 123, Folder 23)
      - Chapel Hill, NC, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 24)
      - Chai Updates, undated, 1990-1991 (Box 123, Folder 25)
      - Church Officials (including Pope), undated, 1987-1988 (Box 123, Folder 26)
      - College Contacts (contains photographs), undated, 1988-1990 (Box 123, Folder 27)
      - Denver, Colorado, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 28)
      - Congregation Sons of Israel, 1989-1990 (Box 123, Folder 29)
      - Crafts Orders - Harburger, undated, 1990-1991 (Box 123, Folder 30)
      - Deressa, Yonas, 1986-1987 (Box 123, Folder 31)
      - Drezek Family, 1988-1989 (Box 123, Folder 32)
      - East Meadow Center (Rabbi Androphy), 1988-1989 (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - Edelstein, Jack, 1986, 1989-1990 (Box 124, Folder 2)
      - Eisen, Gary, 1990 (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - Eisenberg, Rick, 1989 (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - Temple Emanu-El (Oak Park, MI), 1989-1991 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - Temple Emanu-El (Kensington, MD), 1989-1990, 1992 (Box 124, Folder 6)
      - Emanuel Jacob Congregation (Mansfield, OH), 1990 (Box 124, Folder 7)
      - Emounai El (Rabbi Linda Goodman), 1988 (Box 124, Folder 8)
      - Epstein (memory of David Saltzman), 1990 (Box 124, Folder 9)
      - Epstein, Jerry, undated, 1989 (Box 124, Folder 10)
      - Ethiopia: Disease, 1985, 1988-1989 (Box 124, Folder 11)
      - Ethiopia: Famine, General Information, 1986-1987 (Box 124, Folder 12)
      - Ethiopia: Famine, General Information, undated, 1988 (Box 124, Folder 13)
      - Ethiopia: General Information, undated, 1981-1982, 1985-1989 (Box 124, Folder 14)
      - Ethiopia: Live Aid, 1986 (Box 124, Folder 15)
      - Ethiopia: Politics/Government, undated, 1985-1989 (Box 124, Folder 16)
      - Ethiopia: Rebels, General, 1985, 1988-1989 (Box 124, Folder 17)
      - Ethiopia: Refugees from Sudan, 1988-1989 (Box 124, Folder 18)
      - Ethiopia: Resettlement, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 124, Folder 19)
      - Ethiopia: Resettlement Movement of Jews (?), undated, 1985 (Box 124, Folder 20)
      - Ethiopia seize CIA agent, 1986, 1988 (Box 124, Folder 21)
      - Ethiopia-Soviet Ties, undated, 1985-1989 (Box 124, Folder 22)
      - Ethiopia-U.S. Relations, 1987-1989 (Box 124, Folder 23)
      - Ethiopia: Villagization, undated, 1985-1989 (Box 124, Folder 24)
      - Temple Etz Chaim (Rabbi Shimon Paskew), 1988 (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - Family Reunification Master Roster, undated, 1989 (Box 125, Folder 2)
      - Hal Frank, 1988-1989 (Box 125, Folder 3)
      - Jordana Gerson (Oak Park, IL), undated, 1990 (Box 125, Folder 4)
      - Getraer/Rossides, 1990 (Box 125, Folder 5)
      - Rabbi Joseph Glase, 1988 (Box 125, Folder 6)
      - GLOVARR Great Lakes, 1988 (Box 125, Folder 7)
      - Gold, Henry, undated (Box 125, Folder 8)
      - Goodman, Eli, undated, 1986-1989 (Box 125, Folder 9)
      - Margi Greenhut (Chai-Info), undated, 1989-1991 (Box 125, Folder 10)
      - Halpern, Eli, 1987-1989 (Box 125, Folder 11)
      - Hammer, Armand, 1986-1987, 1989 (Box 125, Folder 12)
      - Congregation Har Shalom (Potomac, MD), 1990 (Box 125, Folder 13)
      - Congregation Har Tzeon-Agudath Achim (Rabbi Landman), 1988-1990 (Box 125, Folder 14)
      - Henze, Paul, 1986, 1991 (Box 125, Folder 15)
      - Hershel Religious School (Rabbi J. Goldstein), 1988 (Box 125, Folder 16)
      - Lake Hiawatna Jewish Center, 1988-1989 (Box 125, Folder 17)
      - Hillel Letters, undated, 1991 (Box 125, Folder 18)
      - Dov Hoch and friends of, 1990 (Box 125, Folder 19)
      - Hyman Brand Hebrew Academy (Rabbi Philip Field), 1988 (Box 125, Folder 20)
      - Indianapolis Federation Temple Youth (IFTY), undated, 1989-1990 (Box 125, Folder 21)
      - Temple Israel (Rabbi Shapiro), 1988, 1990 (Box 125, Folder 22)
      - Temple Israel (Silver Spring, MD 20901), undated, 1989-1990 (Box 125, Folder 23)
      - Temple Israel, Silver Spring, MD 20906), 1991 (Box 125, Folder 24)
      - Temple Israel (Sharon, MA), 1990 (Box 125, Folder 25)
      - Temple Israel (Rabbi Steve Pinsky), 1988 (Box 125, Folder 26)
      - Temple Israel (Rabbi Jonathan Brown), 1988 (Box 125, Folder 27)
      - Temple Israel (Naklama Moskowitz), 1989 (Box 125, Folder 28)
      - Temple Israel (Rabbi John Spitzer), 1988 (Box 125, Folder 29)
      - Israel Information, undated, 1992 (Box 125, Folder 30)
      - Israel Programs, undated, 1992 (Box 125, Folder 31)
      - Jewish Federations, Welfare Funds and Community Councils, 1991 (Box 125, Folder 32)
      - Jewish Fellowship of Davis, 1989 (Box 125, Folder 33)
      - "Jewish Survival: The Tale of Three Communities," Baltimore Board of Jewish Education, 1979 (Box 125, Folder 34)
      - Joint Distribution Committee, 1984-1988 (Box 125, Folder 35)
      - Joint Distribution Committee, undated, 1989-1991 (Box 126, Folder 1)
      - Kaye, Hilary (contains photograph), undated, 1986-1987 (Box 126, Folder 2)
      - Temple Kol Ami (Rabbi Norman Roman), 1988 (Box 126, Folder 3)
      - Congregation Kol Emeth (Rabbi Lewis), 1988-1989 (Box 126, Folder 4)
      - Laeffler, David, 1989 (Box 126, Folder 5)
      - Landau, Shirley and Lieberman, Carol, 1988 (Box 126, Folder 6)
      - Letters to Nate Shapiro (and Morton Marcus???), undated, 1984, 1987 (Box 126, Folder 7)
      - Levinson, June, 1990 (Box 126, Folder 8)
      - Liberal Judaism (Rabbi Larry Halpern), 1988 (Box 126, Folder 9)
      - Lookstein, Haskel, 1987 (Box 126, Folder 10)
      - Lovit, Neil, 1988 (Box 126, Folder 11)
      - Margolis, William and Ruth, 1988 (Box 126, Folder 12)
      - Mark Elson Center, Shir-Ami (Rabbi Elliot Strom), 1988-1989 (Box 126, Folder 13)
      - Mason, Ruth, 1987, 1989 (Box 126, Folder 14)
      - Maine Township Jewish Congregation (Rabbi Jan Lapidus), 1988 (Box 126, Folder 15)
      - Marketing Ideas, undated, 1991 (Box 126, Folder 16)
      - Mid-West Association of Reform Rabbis (Rabbi Shimon Moch), 1989 (Box 126, Folder 17)
      - Miller, Rabbi Avis, 1989, 1992 (Box 126, Folder 18)
      - Mishkan Torah Congregation (Robert Goldberg-Strassler), 1988-1989 (Box 126, Folder 19)
      - Mitchell Family, 1988 (Box 126, Folder 20)
      - Montgomery, Ernesto A. Moshe, 1987 (Box 126, Folder 21)
      - Morgenstern, Joel (?), 1987, 1989 (Box 126, Folder 22)
      - Morton, Marcus, undated, 1987-1989 (Box 126, Folder 23)
      - Moss, Jeremy, 1988 (Box 126, Folder 24)
      - Mumeka, Imbuwa, 1990 (Box 126, Folder 25)
      - Mumeka, Lundondo, 1987-1988 (Box 126, Folder 26)
      - Mumeka, Lundondo, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 126, Folder 27)
      - Murphy, Joe, 1986 (Box 126, Folder 28)
      - Myers, James, A., 1988-1989 (Box 126, Folder 29)
      - Bobrow and Nagar (Maplewood, NJ), 1990 (Box 127, Folder 1)
      - Narell, Murray, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 127, Folder 2)
      - Nathan, Abe, undated, 1990 (Box 127, Folder 3)
      - National Council for EJ in Israel, 1985, 1989 (Box 127, Folder 4)
      - NELFTY (Mark Waxman), undated, 1988-1989 (Box 127, Folder 5)
      - Ner Tamid (Rabbi Ronald Shulman), 1988 (Box 127, Folder 6)
      - Neuberg, Jacob, 1989 (Box 127, Folder 7)
      - New Orleans, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 127, Folder 8)
      - North Shore Congregation Israel (Rabbi Stephen Hart), 1988 (Box 127, Folder 9)
      - Congregation Ohav Shalom, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 127, Folder 10)
      - Oheb Shalom (New Jersey), 1990 (Box 127, Folder 11)
      - Ohr Kodesh Congregation, undated, 1987-1988, 1991 (Box 127, Folder 12)
      - Congregation Olam Tikvah (Fairfax, VA), undated, 1990 (Box 127, Folder 13)
      - Old York Road Temple (Rabbi Ronald Kaplan), 1988 (Box 127, Folder 14)
      - Organization for Ethiopian Jewry, 1990 (Box 127, Folder 15)
      - Park Avenue Synagogue (Rabbi Lincoln, Rabbi Wechsler), 1988 (Box 127, Folder 16)
      - Penn Chai, undated, 1990 (Box 127, Folder 17)
      - Pen Pal Names, undated, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 127, Folder 18)
      - People to Call, undated, 1991 (Box 127, Folder 19)
      - Prayers, Poems, Literature, undated, 1984, 1990 (Box 127, Folder 20)
      - Relief: Surgical Aid To Children Of The World (SACOW), undated, 1984-1987 (Box 127, Folder 21)
      - Relief: SACOW Trip Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 127, Folder 22)
      - Rescue Committee for Ethiopian Jews (Ruth Bennet), 1988-1989 (Box 127, Folder 23)
      - Rescue: Family Reunification Plan, Canada, undated, 1985-1988 (Box 127, Folder 24)
      - Rescue: Family Reunification Plan, England, 1984 (Box 127, Folder 25)
      - Rescue: Family Reunification Plan, France, 1986, 1989 (Box 127, Folder 26)
      - Rescue: Family Reunification Plan, Italy, undated, 1986-1989 (Box 127, Folder 27)
      - Rescue: Family Reunification Plan, Rumania, 1986-1987 (Box 127, Folder 28)
      - Rescue: Family Reunification Plan, Sweden, 1985, 1989 (Box 127, Folder 29)
      - Rinaldi, Sarah, undated, 1988-1991 (Box 128, Folder 1)
      - Congregation Rodeh Shalom (Rabbi Ellen Greenspan), 1988, 1990 (Box 128, Folder 2)
      - Congregation Rodeh Shalom (Rabbi Prosnit), 1988 (Box 128, Folder 3)
      - Rosenberg Family, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 4)
      - Rosenberg, Sydney, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 5)
      - Lisa Rosenblatt, undated (Box 128, Folder 6)
      - Rutland Jewish Center, 1989-1990 (Box 128, Folder 7)
      - Samuels, Loulette, 1991 (Box 128, Folder 8)
      - Santa Monica Synagogue (Rabbi Jeffery Perry-Marx), 1988 (Box 128, Folder 9)
      - Congregation Schaarai Zedek (Richard Birnholz), 1988 (Box 128, Folder 10)
      - Schacter, Hal, 1990 (Box 128, Folder 11)
      - Schwarz, Gladys, 1989-1990 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - Shaare Tefila (Rabbi Halpern), undated, 1988-1990 (Box 128, Folder 13)
      - Shaare Tikvah, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 14)
      - Temple Shaaray Tefila, 1988-1990 (Box 128, Folder 15)
      - Temple Shaari Emeth (P. Schechter), 1985-1986 (Box 128, Folder 16)
      - Temple Shalom (Chevy Chase, MD), 1990 (Box 128, Folder 17)
      - Temple Shalom, New Jersey, 1989-1990 (Box 128, Folder 18)
      - Shalom (Stanley Schickler), 1988 (Box 128, Folder 19)
      - Temple Sharey-Tefilo Israel, undated, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 20)
      - Congregation Sherith Israel, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 21)
      - Shir Ha'Maalat - Harber Reform Temple, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 22)
      - Shlomo Mula Lecture Tour, undated, 1991-1992 (Box 128, Folder 23)
      - Shomrei Torah, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 24)
      - Temple Sinai, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 25)
      - Temple Solel (Rabbi Bell), 1988-1989 (Box 128, Folder 26)
      - Temple Solel, Bowie, MD, 1989-1990 (Box 128, Folder 27)
      - Southeast Hebrew Congregation, 1989-1990 (Box 128, Folder 28)
      - Stakten Jewish Welfare Fund, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 29)
      - Stewart, Mikael, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 30)
      - Stillman Family, undated, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 31)
      - Storage USA, undated, 1991 (Box 128, Folder 32)
      - Student Action for Ethiopian Jews, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 33)
      - Tefereth Israel Congregation (Rabbi Nathan Abromowitz), 1988-1989 (Box 128, Folder 34)
      - Twinning, March-April 1992 (Box 128, Folder 35)
      - Twinning, June 1992 (Box 128, Folder 36)
      - Twinning, July 1992 (Box 128, Folder 37)
      - United Jewish Appeal of Easton (Leonard Kornet), 1989 (Box 128, Folder 38)
      - Vargas, Angela, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 39)
      - Washington Hebrew, 1989-1991 (Box 128, Folder 40)
      - Weinreb, Marvin, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 41)
      - Wiesel, Eli, undated, 1984, 1986-1987 (Box 128, Folder 42)
      - Woll, Sharon and Friends, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 43)
      - Woodlands Community Temple, 1988 (Box 128, Folder 44)
      - World Union of Jewish Students - "Fact Finding Mission to Ethiopia", June 1990 (Box 128, Folder 45)
      - Young Israel Shomrai Emunah, undated, 1988-1989 (Box 128, Folder 46)
    - Subseries 2: AAEJ Washington DC Recant: Congress: General Files A-Z, undated, 1979, 1982-1993; Boxes 129-130.
      The series consists of Recant's correspondence with politicians, arranged alphabetically by last name. The correspondence dates from 1979 to 1993.
      - AAEJ Congressional Advocacy, Packet, undated, 1986, 1991-1992 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - Caucus, General, undated, 1986, 1990-1991 (Box 129, Folder 2)
      - Money for Ethiopian Jews in Israel / Absorption, undated, 1979, 1982-1983, 1985-1989 (Box 129, Folder 3)
      - State Department - Congress Correspondence, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 129, Folder 4)
      - Ackerman, Rep. Gary (D-NY) (contains photograph), undated, 1984-1992 (Box 129, Folder 5)
      - Annunzio, Rep. Frank (D-IL), 1986 (Box 129, Folder 6)
      - Armstrong, William ( - CO), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 7)
      - Atkins, Rep. Chester (D-MA), 1985 (Box 129, Folder 8)
      - Bates, Rep. Jim, 1989 (Box 129, Folder 9)
      - Bentsen, Sen. Lloyd (D-TX), 1985-1986 (Box 129, Folder 10)
      - Berman, Rep. Howard (D-CA), 1983, 1985-1986 (Box 129, Folder 11)
      - Biaggi, Rep. Mario (D-NY), 1984-1985 (Box 129, Folder 12)
      - Boschwitz, Sen. Rudy (R-MN) (contains photograph), undated, 1984, 1986-1987, 1989-1990, 1992-1993 (Box 129, Folder 13)
      - Bradley, Sen. Bill (D-NJ), 1985, 1989-1990 (Box 129, Folder 14)
      - Brown, Hank (R-CO), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 15)
      - Burdick, Sen. Quentin (D-ND), 1987-1988 (Box 129, Folder 16)
      - Burton, Rep. Dan (R-IN), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 17)
      - Byrd, Sen. Robert (D-WV), 1986 (Box 129, Folder 18)
      - Campbell, Rep. Ben Nighthorse ( - CO), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 19)
      - Campbell, Rep. Tom (R-CA), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 20)
      - Chiles, Sen. Lawton (D-FL), 1986-1987 (Box 129, Folder 21)
      - Coehlo, Rep. Tony (D-CA), 1987 (Box 129, Folder 22)
      - Cohen, Sen. William (R-ME), 1984 (Box 129, Folder 23)
      - Courter, Jim (NJ), 1985 (Box 129, Folder 24)
      - Cox, Rep. Christopher (R-CA), 1990 (Box 129, Folder 25)
      - Cranston, Sen. Alan (D-CA) (contains photograph), undated, 1985-1989, 1991-1992 (Box 129, Folder 26)
      - D'Amato, Sen. Alfonse (R-NY), undated, 1985-1987, 1990 (Box 129, Folder 27)
      - Dellums, Rep. Ronald (D-CA), 1987 (Box 129, Folder 28)
      - Deloncini, Sen. Dennis (D-AZ), undated, 1984-1986 (Box 129, Folder 29)
      - Dixon, Sen. Alan J. (D-IL), undated, 1988-1989 (Box 129, Folder 30)
      - Dodd, Sen. Christopher (D-CT), 1985 (Box 129, Folder 31)
      - Dole, Sen. Bob (R-KS), 1986 (Box 129, Folder 32)
      - Dreier, Rep. David (R-CA), 1987 (Box 129, Folder 33)
      - Durbin, Rep. Richard (D-IL), 1986 (Box 129, Folder 34)
      - Dwyer, Rep. Bernard (D-NJ), 1986, 1988 (Box 129, Folder 35)
      - Edwards, Rep. Don (D-CA), 1986 (Box 129, Folder 36)
      - Engel, Rep. Eliot L. (D-NY), 1989 (Box 129, Folder 37)
      - Fascell, Rep. Dante (D-FL) (contains photograph), undated, 1986-1987, 1991 (Box 129, Folder 38)
      - Feighan, Rep. Edward (D-OH), 1986-1987 (Box 129, Folder 39)
      - Flake, Rep. Floyd H. (D-NY), 1988 (Box 129, Folder 40)
      - Frank, Rep. Barney (D-MA) (contains photograph), undated, 1984-1985, 1989 (Box 129, Folder 41)
      - Gallegly, Rep. Elton (R-CA), 1988 (Box 129, Folder 42)
      - Gallo, Rep. Dean, 1989 (Box 129, Folder 43)
      - Gilman, Rep. Ben (R-NY), undated, 1986, 1988-1989, 1991-1992 (Box 129, Folder 44)